Guide to the Health Association of Cattaraugus County records, [ca.1909]-1960.
Health Association of Cattaraugus County records,
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Health Association of Cattaraugus County records, [ca.1909]-1960.
2890
Health Association of Cattaraugus County.
4.8 cubic ft.
Organizational records, correspondence, and research.
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Includes histories of the Health Association of Cattaraugus County, Board of Directors and Executive Committee minutes, scrapbooks of Association activities, and correspondence.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Includes histories of the Health Association of Cattaraugus County, 1908-1960, Board of Directors and Executive Committee minutes, 1931-1948, scrapbooks of Association activities, and correspondence.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Health Association of Cattaraugus County.
Subjects:
Health.; Health planning -- New York (State) -- Cattaraugus County.; Political science
Places:
Cattaraugus County (N.Y.) -- Politics and government.; New York (State) -- Cattaraugus County
INFORMATION FOR USERS
CONTAINER LIST
- Board of Directors and Executive Committee of the Health Association of Cattaraugus County and Allegany, NY Health Committee Meeting Minutes (Box 1)
- Anti-tuberculosis Activity in Catt.Co. prior to Milbank Demonstration, Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Anti-tuberculosis Activity in Catt.Co. prior to Milbank Demonstration, Undated; Bradley, Florence (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Report of Study of Program, Organization and Administration of HA of CC Inc. and CC Heart Chapter, 1960-05; Bradley, Florence; State TB Committee; NY Heart Assembly; State Charities Aid Association (SCAA) (Box 2, Folder 3)
  Palmer, F.
  Eaton, B.
- Sample Appendices for Report of Study of Program… (File #3), 1960-05 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Papers re Lilla C. Wheeler (Important), Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
  Wheeler, Lilla C.
- Miscellaneous minutes and correspondence, 1931-1945 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Minutes of Board of Directors, 1943-1947 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Minutes of Board of Directors, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Minutes of Board of Directors, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Death of Dr. Greenleaf, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Sale of Bartlett House to County, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- County Vouchers re Bartlett House, 1954-1959 (Box 2, Folder 12)
- Correspondence re giving up Bartlett House, Undated; Laughlin, Nancy Bartlett (Box 2, Folder 13)
- Bartlett House re insurance and repairs, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Bartlett House: paint, boiler, fire extinguisher. Recommend by fire chief. Key sample, policies re maintenance, etc., 1955 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- Financial statements re Bartlett Memorial Community Center, 1954-1956 (Box 2, Folder 16)
- Financial statements re Bartlett Memorial Community Center, 1954-1961 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Financial statements re Bartlett Memorial Community Center, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 18)
- Financial statements re Bartlett Memorial Community Center, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Bartlett House re rents, parking in drive, need for more room, use of rooms, etc., 1946-1961 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Press Service (Anti-Tuberculosis) of State Charities Aid Ass'n., 1909 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Reports and important information about establishment of Olean City Health Dept. office, 1908-1922 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- Booklets and other official publications about the demonstration in Cattaraugus County, Undated (Box 2, Folder 23)
  Bradley, Florence
  Clark, J. C.
  Mandeville, William H.
  Moon, Eve
  Wheeler, Lilla
  Greenleaf
  Williams, Allan B.
  Hoaglund, Verna
- Report of Olean Health Demonstration by George Nelbach of State Charities Aid Ass'n., Undated (Box 2, Folder 24)
- Re an American Dietetic Ass'n exhibit used by CCTB and PH, 1957 (Box 2, Folder 25)
- Closing of Rocky Crest Sanitarium in 1950, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  RCS had started in 1916, but 1946 State Law reduced State Aid to counties.
- Christmas Seal Sale records, 1921-1926 (Box 2, Folder 27)
- Christmas Seal Sale records, 1922-1927 (Box 2, Folder 28)
- Christmas Seal Sale records, 1928-1929 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  luncheon program with songs
- Christmas Seal Sale records, 1929-1948 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  memo from George Nelbach
- Original program for 1930 C.S. luncheon at Bartlett Memorial Community Center, 1930 (Box 2, Folder 31)
- CS reports for 1930, 1931, 1932, 1930-1932 (Box 2, Folder 32)
  Laughlin, Nancy Bartlett
- CS reports for 1933, 1934, 1935, 1933-1935 (Box 2, Folder 33)
- CS Citations with totals received, 1949-1960 (Box 2, Folder 34)
- Cattaraugus County Health Camp, Inventories; report, including staff names, 1923-1924 (Box 2, Folder 35)
- Catt. Co. Health Camp Reports and Menu, 1923-1929 (Box 2, Folder 36)
- Catt. Co. Health Camp Reports, Menu, and The Health Camper, Vol 1, No 1 Statistics, 1923-1936 (Box 2, Folder 37)
- Catt. Co. Health Camp and Miscellaneous Reports, 1923-1937 (Box 2, Folder 38)
- Catt. Co. Health Camp, 1937 (Box 2, Folder 39)
- Catt. Co. Health Camp Names of Children and Registration Figures, 1923-1935 (Box 2, Folder 40)
- Catt. Co. Health Camp Reports, 1925 (Box 2, Folder 41)
- Newsletter from office to directors, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 42)
- Newsletter from office to directors, 1938 (Box 2, Folder 43)
- Health Newscast, 1951-1952 (Box 2, Folder 44)
- Health Newscast, 1923-1955 (Box 2, Folder 45)
- Health Newscast, 1956-1957 (Box 2, Folder 46)
- Health Newscast, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 47)
- Health Newscast, 1958 (Box 2, Folder 48)
- Photo of Fair Exhibit, Undated; Photographs (Box 2, Folder 49)
- Photos of volunteers at exhibits, folding and stuffing Christmas Seal mail, etc., Undated; Photographs (Box 2, Folder 50)
- Oversized picture of Dr. Greenleaf, Undated; Photographs (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Photo of Wheeler Memorial cottage at Trudeau Sanatorium in Saranac, Undated; Photographs (Box 2, Folder 52)
  Portrait of Dr. Trudeau
- Snapshots of Fair Exhibit, Undated; Photographs (Box 2, Folder 53)
- Original reports typed by Florence Bradley and by Ella Finch, 1908-1921 (Box 2, Folder 54)
- Allehany Health Committee's Activities, 1953-1959 (Box 2, Folder 55)
  Finch, Ella
- Allehany Health Committee's Activities, 1953-1959 (Box 2, Folder 56)
- Allehany Health Committee's Activities, 1953-1959 (Box 2, Folder 57)
- Allehany Health Committee's Activities, 1953-1959 (Box 2, Folder 58)
- Allehany Health Committee's Activities, 1953-1959 (Box 2, Folder 59)
- Allehany Health Committee's Activities, 1953-1959 (Box 2, Folder 60)
- Allehany Health Committee's Activities, 1953-1959 (Box 2, Folder 61)
- Allehany Health Committee's Activities, 1953-1959 (Box 2, Folder 62)
- Allehany Health Committee's Activities, 1953-1959 (Box 2, Folder 63)
- Allegany Health Committee Immunization lists, 1955-1957 (Box 2, Folder 64)
- Allegany Health Committee Immunization lists, Undated (Box 2, Folder 65)
- Allegany Health Committee Antidotes for poison and Correspondence, 1957-1959 (Box 2, Folder 66)
- Allegany Health Association (Committee) Poison Control, 1956 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Allegany Health Association (Committee) Safety campaign, Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Franklinville Health Committee, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Franklinville Health Committee, 1954 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- Little Valley Health Committee, 1955 (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Randolph Area Health Education Comm., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Randolph Area Health Education Comm., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  Health Association withdraws its support
- Randolph Area Health Education Comm., Undated (Box 3, Folder 8)
  Inception and Correspondence with Anna Hooley
  Hooley, Anna
- Randolph Area Health Ed., 1954 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Milbank Fund and Tuberculosis Hospital, 1898-1908 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  Nelbach, George
- Health Education Project in Cattaraugus County and Reports to Milbank Fund, 1931-1937 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Publications related to Milbank Health Demonstration, Undated (Box 3)
- The Health Association Annual Report for 1954 "Homespun", 1954 (Box 3)
- An article on "the individuality of the child versus the system" by Kingsley, 1913 (Box 3)
- Additional scrapbooks (Box 4)
- Scrapbook for Newspaper Clippings, 1908-1927 (Box 5)
- "Standard B&P Scrapbook", 1909-1919 (Box 6)
- Brown leather scrapbook, 1940-1943 (Box 6)
- Christmas Seal Sale Scrapbook, 1953 (Box 6)
- Community X-ray Surveys Scrapbook, 1947 (Box 6)